GustavoPenha

guzpenha10@gmail.com

about 28 years Delft, NL
links webpage twitter github google scholar
programming Python, C++, Spark, R
languages portuguese english

soft skills time management communication learn and adapt

research

2022

I am a researcher in the fields of Information Retrieval, Recommender Systems, Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing. My PhD is focused on ranking models for conversational search & recommendation.

Pairwise Review-Based Explanations for Voice Product Search

selected publications

	Gustavo Penha, Eyal Krikon, Vanessa Murdock
2022	Evaluating the Robustness of Retrieval Pipelines with Query Variation Generators Best paper award @ECIR Gustavo Penha, Arthur Câmara, Claudia Hauff
2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural Learning to Rank Models for Conversational Search EACL Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	What does BERT know about books, movies and music? Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation RecSys Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR: An Empirical Study on Conversation Response Ranking Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff

experience

2022-6–8	Research Intern Spotify - NL Research on synthetic query generation for improving retrievability of entities.
2021-5–8	Applied Research Intern Research on explanations for Alexa, published 2 papers (CHI'22 & CHIIR'22).
2015–2018	Data Scientist Machine learning and data science projects. Tech lead of 1M+ R\$ project.
2014–2015	Undergraduate Researcher UFMG - Brazil Research on scientific collaboration networks. Coauthor in 2 papers.

education

2019–now	Ph.D. TU Delft - Netherlands Computer Science. <i>10 papers, 100+ citations and 150+ github stars.</i>
2012–2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc. UFMG - Brazil Computer Science. <i>MSc work won best paper RU award at RecSys'20.</i>